<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><MD_Metadata xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:srv="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/srv" xmlns:gts="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gts" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:gco="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gco" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gmd">
    <language>
        <LanguageCode codeList="http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/php/code_list.php" codeListValue="eng" codeSpace="ISO639-2">eng</LanguageCode>
    </language>
    <characterSet>
        <MD_CharacterSetCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_CharacterSetCode" codeListValue="utf8" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">utf8</MD_CharacterSetCode>
    </characterSet>
    <hierarchyLevel>
        <MD_ScopeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_ScopeCode" codeListValue="dataset" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">dataset</MD_ScopeCode>
    </hierarchyLevel>
    <hierarchyLevelName>
        <gco:CharacterString>dataset</gco:CharacterString>
    </hierarchyLevelName>
    <contact gco:nilReason="missing"/>
    <dateStamp>
        <gco:Date>2012-01-23</gco:Date>
    </dateStamp>
    <metadataStandardName>
        <gco:CharacterString>ISO 19139 Geographic Information - Metadata - Implementation Specification</gco:CharacterString>
    </metadataStandardName>
    <metadataStandardVersion>
        <gco:CharacterString>2007</gco:CharacterString>
    </metadataStandardVersion>
    <spatialRepresentationInfo>
        <MD_VectorSpatialRepresentation>
            <topologyLevel>
                <MD_TopologyLevelCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopologyLevelCode" codeListValue="geometryOnly" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">geometryOnly</MD_TopologyLevelCode>
            </topologyLevel>
            <geometricObjects>
                <MD_GeometricObjects>
                    <geometricObjectType>
                        <MD_GeometricObjectTypeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_GeometricObjectTypeCode" codeListValue="composite" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">composite</MD_GeometricObjectTypeCode>
                    </geometricObjectType>
                </MD_GeometricObjects>
            </geometricObjects>
        </MD_VectorSpatialRepresentation>
    </spatialRepresentationInfo>
    <referenceSystemInfo>
        <MD_ReferenceSystem>
            <referenceSystemIdentifier>
                <RS_Identifier>
                    <code>
                        <gco:CharacterString>4326</gco:CharacterString>
                    </code>
                    <codeSpace>
                        <gco:CharacterString>EPSG</gco:CharacterString>
                    </codeSpace>
                    <version>
                        <gco:CharacterString>7.4.1</gco:CharacterString>
                    </version>
                </RS_Identifier>
            </referenceSystemIdentifier>
        </MD_ReferenceSystem>
    </referenceSystemInfo>
    <identificationInfo>
        <MD_DataIdentification>
            <citation>
                <CI_Citation>
                    <title>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Freshwater Ecoregions Of the World (FEOW)</gco:CharacterString>
                    </title>
                    <date>
                        <CI_Date>
                            <date>
                                <gco:Date>2008-01-01</gco:Date>
                            </date>
                            <dateType>
                                <CI_DateTypeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#CI_DateTypeCode" codeListValue="publication" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">publication</CI_DateTypeCode>
                            </dateType>
                        </CI_Date>
                    </date>
                    <citedResponsibleParty>
                        <CI_ResponsibleParty>
                            <organisationName>
                                <gco:CharacterString>The Nature Conservancy (slightly altering the original version by TNC and WWF, Inc., to include Major Habitat Types in the tabular data.)</gco:CharacterString>
                            </organisationName>
                            <role>
                                <CI_RoleCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#CI_RoleCode" codeListValue="originator" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">originator</CI_RoleCode>
                            </role>
                        </CI_ResponsibleParty>
                    </citedResponsibleParty>
                    <presentationForm>
                        <CI_PresentationFormCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#CI_PresentationFormCode" codeListValue="mapDigital" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">mapDigital</CI_PresentationFormCode>
                    </presentationForm>
                    <otherCitationDetails>
                        <gco:CharacterString>TNC is the originator of this version of the FEOW. Ecoregion names, codes, and boundaries are identical to those in the published version by TNC and WWF, Inc. This version differs as it also includes Major Habitat Types and a 5-digit ecoregion ID. Citation for the Ecoregions: Robin Abell, Michele L. Thieme, Carmen Revenga, Mark Bryer, Maurice Kottelat, Nina Bogutskaya, Brian Coad, Nick Mandrak, Salvador Contreras Balderas, William Bussing, Melanie L. J. Stiassny, Paul Skelton, Gerald R. Allen, Peter Unmack, Alexander Naseka, Rebecca Ng, Nikolai Sindorf, James Robertson, Eric Armijo, Jonathan V. Higgins, Thomas J. Heibel, Eric Wikramanayake, David Olson, Hugo L. López, Roberto E. Reis, John G. Lundberg, Mark H. Sabaj Pérez, and Paulo Petry. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414. Citation for the Major Habitat Types: TNC and WWF, Inc. 2008. Freshwater Major Habitat Types. Unpublished digital media modified from: Abell et al. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414.</gco:CharacterString>
                    </otherCitationDetails>
                </CI_Citation>
            </citation>
            <abstract>
                <gco:CharacterString>The Freshwater Ecoregions Of the World (FEOW) provide a global biogeographic regionalization of the Earth's freshwater biodiversity. This version of the FEOW, modified by The Nature Conservancy, includes additional tabular data describing Major Habitat Types (MHTs, similar to terrestrial biomes, but unpublished). You can read more about the FEOW, and obtain the unmodified shapefile at www.feow.org. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World, (FEOW) provides a new global biogeographic regionalization of the Earth's freshwater biodiversity. Covering virtually all freshwater habitats on Earth, this first-ever ecoregion map, together with associated species data, is a useful tool for underpinning global and regional conservation planning efforts, particularly to identify outstanding and imperiled freshwater systems; for serving as a logical framework for large-scale conservation strategies; and for providing a global-scale knowledge base for increasing freshwater biogeographic literacy. This version of the FEOW, modified by The Nature Conservancy, includes additional tabular data describing Major Habitat Types (MHTs, similar to terrestrial biomes). These MHTs were developed by TNC and WWF, Inc., but have not undergone rigorous review and are as of yet unpublished. All ecoregions are nested within the eleven MHTs' boundaries.Purpose: The freshwater ecoregion map serves as a complement to the global terrestrial and marine ecoregion maps and differs from them in that freshwater species (primarily fish) and freshwater processes drove the map delineation. Freshwater Major Habitat Types (MHTs) are included in the TNC version of the FEOWin addition to the ecoregion names and IDs already in the published FEOW version. These MHTs have value in comparing ecoregions of similar broad habitats across the globe.Supplemental information: The freshwater ecoregion map encompasses 426 units, whose boundaries generally - though not always - correspond with those of watersheds (also known as drainage basins or catchments). Within individual ecoregions there will be turnover of species, such as when moving up or down a river system, but taken as a whole an ecoregion will typically have a distinct evolutionary history and/or ecological processes. Ecoregions are delineated based on the best available information, but data describing freshwater species and ecological processes are characterized by marked gaps and variation in quality, and improved information in the future may warrant map revisions. Citation for the Ecoregions: Robin Abell, Michele L. Thieme, Carmen Revenga, Mark Bryer, Maurice Kottelat, Nina Bogutskaya, Brian Coad, Nick Mandrak, Salvador Contreras Balderas, William Bussing, Melanie L. J. Stiassny, Paul Skelton, Gerald R. Allen, Peter Unmack, Alexander Naseka, Rebecca Ng, Nikolai Sindorf, James Robertson, Eric Armijo, Jonathan V. Higgins, Thomas J. Heibel, Eric Wikramanayake, David Olson, Hugo L. López, Roberto E. Reis, John G. Lundberg, Mark H. Sabaj Pérez, and Paulo Petry. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414. Citation for the Major Habitat Types: TNC and WWF, Inc. 2008. Freshwater Major Habitat Types. Unpublished digital media modified from: Abell et al. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414.</gco:CharacterString>
            </abstract>
            <purpose>
                <gco:CharacterString>The Freshwater Ecoregions Of the World (FEOW) provide a global biogeographic regionalization of the Earth's Freshwater biodiversity. This version, Nature Conservancy-modified, includes additional tabular data describing Major Habitat Types (MHTs).</gco:CharacterString>
            </purpose>
            <credit>
                <gco:CharacterString>The Nature Conservancy and World Wildlife Fund, Inc. The Major Habitat Types are an unpublished addition for this version of the FEOW provided for the purpose of global reporting by The Nature Conservancy.</gco:CharacterString>
            </credit>
            <status>
                <MD_ProgressCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_ProgressCode" codeListValue="completed" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">completed</MD_ProgressCode>
            </status>
            <pointOfContact>
                <CI_ResponsibleParty>
                    <individualName>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Central Science Team</gco:CharacterString>
                    </individualName>
                    <organisationName>
                        <gco:CharacterString>The Nature Conservancy</gco:CharacterString>
                    </organisationName>
                    <contactInfo>
                        <CI_Contact>
                            <address>
                                <CI_Address>
                                    <deliveryPoint>
                                        <gco:CharacterString>4245 N. Fairfax Drive, Suite 100</gco:CharacterString>
                                    </deliveryPoint>
                                    <city>
                                        <gco:CharacterString>Arlington</gco:CharacterString>
                                    </city>
                                    <administrativeArea>
                                        <gco:CharacterString>VA</gco:CharacterString>
                                    </administrativeArea>
                                    <postalCode>
                                        <gco:CharacterString>22203</gco:CharacterString>
                                    </postalCode>
                                    <country>
                                        <Country codeList="http://www.iso.org/iso/country_codes/iso_3166_code_lists.htm" codeListValue="US" codeSpace="ISO3166-1">US</Country>
                                    </country>
                                </CI_Address>
                            </address>
                            <contactInstructions>
                                <gco:CharacterString>See http://maps.tnc.org</gco:CharacterString>
                            </contactInstructions>
                        </CI_Contact>
                    </contactInfo>
                    <role>
                        <CI_RoleCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#CI_RoleCode" codeListValue="pointOfContact" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">pointOfContact</CI_RoleCode>
                    </role>
                </CI_ResponsibleParty>
            </pointOfContact>
            <resourceMaintenance>
                <MD_MaintenanceInformation>
                    <maintenanceAndUpdateFrequency>
                        <MD_MaintenanceFrequencyCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_MaintenanceFrequencyCode" codeListValue="asNeeded" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">asNeeded</MD_MaintenanceFrequencyCode>
                    </maintenanceAndUpdateFrequency>
                </MD_MaintenanceInformation>
            </resourceMaintenance>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>global</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <type>
                        <MD_KeywordTypeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_KeywordTypeCode" codeListValue="place" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">place</MD_KeywordTypeCode>
                    </type>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>freshwater fish biogeography biodiversity</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <type>
                        <MD_KeywordTypeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_KeywordTypeCode" codeListValue="theme" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">theme</MD_KeywordTypeCode>
                    </type>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Downloadable Data</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <thesaurusName uuidref="723f6998-058e-11dc-8314-0800200c9a66"/>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_Constraints>
                    <useLimitation>
                        <gco:CharacterString>The data are suitable for public use. Staff of The Nature Conservancy should contact Jim Platt to learn additional ways - including REST endpoints - to access the Conservancy's internal information or visit our Intranet page. You can show these map services in your own application if you like; the only condition being that The Nature Conservancy is listed as the author, you are using the data for noncommercial purposes, and you don't alter them in any way.</gco:CharacterString>
                    </useLimitation>
                </MD_Constraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_LegalConstraints>
                    <accessConstraints>
                        <MD_RestrictionCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_RestrictionCode" codeListValue="otherRestrictions" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">otherRestrictions</MD_RestrictionCode>
                    </accessConstraints>
                    <otherConstraints>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Access constraints: Copyright 2008 by The Nature Conservancy and World Wildlife Fund, Inc. All Rights Reserved. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World (FEOW) has been jointly developed by the Conservation Science Program of World Wildlife Fund and by The Nature Conservancy. Some content on this site may be the property of independent authors and contributors, who may be identified in separate copyright notices associated with content provided by them. You may not copy, reproduce, modify, display, republish, upload, post, transmit, distribute, alter, prepare any derivative works of, or otherwise use any material from this web site, including without limitation text, code, software, photographs, and images, without the prior express written consent of The Nature Conservancy or World Wildlife Fund, except as described below.</gco:CharacterString>
                    </otherConstraints>
                </MD_LegalConstraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_LegalConstraints>
                    <useConstraints>
                        <MD_RestrictionCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_RestrictionCode" codeListValue="otherRestrictions" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">otherRestrictions</MD_RestrictionCode>
                    </useConstraints>
                    <otherConstraints>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Use constraints: You may use the content for non-commercial, educational, or scientific conservation purposes, provided that: (1) The above copyright notice or any separate copyright notice that appears with the content must appear on all copies, along with a citation (and a link, in the case of online use) to http://www.feow.org; (2) you may use only so much of the content as is reasonably necessary to accomplish your non-commercial, educational, or scientific purpose; (3) you may not make any material modifications to the portion of the content you use; and (4) you may not use graphics or photographs separately from the accompanying text.</gco:CharacterString>
                    </otherConstraints>
                </MD_LegalConstraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_SecurityConstraints>
                    <classification>
                        <MD_ClassificationCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_ClassificationCode" codeListValue="unclassified" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">unclassified</MD_ClassificationCode>
                    </classification>
                </MD_SecurityConstraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <aggregationInfo>
                <MD_AggregateInformation>
                    <aggregateDataSetName>
                        <CI_Citation>
                            <title>
                                <gco:CharacterString>Freshwater Ecoregions of the World (FEOW)</gco:CharacterString>
                            </title>
                            <date gco:nilReason="missing"/>
                            <edition>
                                <gco:CharacterString>First</gco:CharacterString>
                            </edition>
                            <citedResponsibleParty>
                                <CI_ResponsibleParty>
                                    <organisationName>
                                        <gco:CharacterString>The Nature Conservancy</gco:CharacterString>
                                    </organisationName>
                                    <role>
                                        <CI_RoleCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#CI_RoleCode" codeListValue="originator" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">originator</CI_RoleCode>
                                    </role>
                                </CI_ResponsibleParty>
                            </citedResponsibleParty>
                            <otherCitationDetails>
                                <gco:CharacterString>Robin Abell, Michele L. Thieme, Carmen Revenga, Mark Bryer, Maurice Kottelat, Nina Bogutskaya, Brian Coad, Nick Mandrak, Salvador Contreras Balderas, William Bussing, Melanie L. J. Stiassny, Paul Skelton, Gerald R. Allen, Peter Unmack, Alexander Naseka, Rebecca Ng, Nikolai Sindorf, James Robertson, Eric Armijo, Jonathan V. Higgins, Thomas J. Heibel, Eric Wikramanayake, David Olson, Hugo L. López, Roberto E. Reis, John G. Lundberg, Mark H. Sabaj Pérez, and Paulo Petry. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414.</gco:CharacterString>
                            </otherCitationDetails>
                        </CI_Citation>
                    </aggregateDataSetName>
                    <associationType>
                        <DS_AssociationTypeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#DS_AssociationTypeCode" codeListValue="crossReference" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">crossReference</DS_AssociationTypeCode>
                    </associationType>
                </MD_AggregateInformation>
            </aggregationInfo>
            <spatialRepresentationType>
                <MD_SpatialRepresentationTypeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_SpatialRepresentationTypeCode" codeListValue="vector" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">vector</MD_SpatialRepresentationTypeCode>
            </spatialRepresentationType>
            <language>
                <LanguageCode codeList="http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/php/code_list.php" codeListValue="eng" codeSpace="ISO639-2">eng</LanguageCode>
            </language>
            <characterSet>
                <MD_CharacterSetCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_CharacterSetCode" codeListValue="utf8" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">utf8</MD_CharacterSetCode>
            </characterSet>
            <environmentDescription>
                <gco:CharacterString>ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.2.3200</gco:CharacterString>
            </environmentDescription>
            <extent>
                <EX_Extent>
                    <description>
                        <gco:CharacterString>publication date</gco:CharacterString>
                    </description>
                    <geographicElement>
                        <EX_GeographicBoundingBox>
                            <extentTypeCode>
                                <gco:Boolean>true</gco:Boolean>
                            </extentTypeCode>
                            <westBoundLongitude>
                                <gco:Decimal>-180</gco:Decimal>
                            </westBoundLongitude>
                            <eastBoundLongitude>
                                <gco:Decimal>180</gco:Decimal>
                            </eastBoundLongitude>
                            <southBoundLatitude>
                                <gco:Decimal>-90</gco:Decimal>
                            </southBoundLatitude>
                            <northBoundLatitude>
                                <gco:Decimal>83.623596</gco:Decimal>
                            </northBoundLatitude>
                        </EX_GeographicBoundingBox>
                    </geographicElement>
                    <temporalElement>
                        <EX_TemporalExtent>
                            <extent>
                                <gml:TimeInstant gml:id="N66604">
                                    <gml:timePosition indeterminatePosition="unknown"/>
                                </gml:TimeInstant>
                            </extent>
                        </EX_TemporalExtent>
                    </temporalElement>
                </EX_Extent>
            </extent>
            <supplementalInformation>
                <gco:CharacterString>The freshwater ecoregion map encompasses 426 units, whose boundaries generally - though not always - correspond with those of watersheds (also known as drainage basins or catchments). Within individual ecoregions there will be turnover of species, such as when moving up or down a river system, but taken as a whole an ecoregion will typically have a distinct evolutionary history and/or ecological processes. Ecoregions are delineated based on the best available information, but data describing freshwater species and ecological processes are characterized by marked gaps and variation in quality, and improved information in the future may warrant map revisions. Citation for the Ecoregions: Robin Abell, Michele L. Thieme, Carmen Revenga, Mark Bryer, Maurice Kottelat, Nina Bogutskaya, Brian Coad, Nick Mandrak, Salvador Contreras Balderas, William Bussing, Melanie L. J. Stiassny, Paul Skelton, Gerald R. Allen, Peter Unmack, Alexander Naseka, Rebecca Ng, Nikolai Sindorf, James Robertson, Eric Armijo, Jonathan V. Higgins, Thomas J. Heibel, Eric Wikramanayake, David Olson, Hugo L. López, Roberto E. Reis, John G. Lundberg, Mark H. Sabaj Pérez, and Paulo Petry. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414. Citation for the Major Habitat Types: TNC and WWF, Inc. 2008. Freshwater Major Habitat Types. Unpublished digital media modified from: Abell et al. 2008. Freshwater Ecoregions of the World: A New Map of Biogeographic Units for Freshwater Biodiversity Conservation. BioScience. Vol. 58 No. 5: 403-414.</gco:CharacterString>
            </supplementalInformation>
        </MD_DataIdentification>
    </identificationInfo>
    <distributionInfo>
        <MD_Distribution>
            <distributionFormat>
                <MD_Format>
                    <name>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Shapefile</gco:CharacterString>
                    </name>
                    <version gco:nilReason="missing"/>
                </MD_Format>
            </distributionFormat>
            <transferOptions>
                <MD_DigitalTransferOptions>
                    <transferSize>
                        <gco:Real>21.18</gco:Real>
                    </transferSize>
                </MD_DigitalTransferOptions>
            </transferOptions>
        </MD_Distribution>
    </distributionInfo>
</MD_Metadata>
